<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mobile on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mobile on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCalc - React Native - Deep Dive (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-07-23_opencalc-react-native-deep-dive-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-07-23_opencalc-react-native-deep-dive-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This is part 2 of a 2 part series on OpenCalc, an open-source mobile calculator built with react-native, javascript and flow. The first part dealt with the design and UI components and a previous post addressed writing the app the app market in general. The second part will deal with the calculation and validation. OpenCalc is available on iOS and Android.
  OpenCalc in action   The main controller has a property called brain, which is an instance of CalculatorBrain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCalc - React Native - Deep Dive (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-07-05_opencalc-react-native-deep-dive-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-07-05_opencalc-react-native-deep-dive-part-1/</guid>
      <description>OpenCalc is a mobile calculator written in React Native. Below is a deep dive on the inner workings and design decisions I made on OpenCalc
OpenCalc is a mobile calculator written in React Native. This is my first app using React Native and JavaScript. Below is a deep dive on the inner workings and design decisions I made on OpenCalc…
OpenCalc is a mobile calculator written in React Native. This is my first app using React Native and JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Free Open-Source iPad Calculator and Why Your App Won&#39;t Make You Any Money</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-06-28_a-free-open-source-ipad-calculator-and-why-your-app-won-t-make-you-any-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/blog/2018-06-28_a-free-open-source-ipad-calculator-and-why-your-app-won-t-make-you-any-money/</guid>
      <description>After an unsatisfactory selection of free (free to download, no ads/tracking or in app purchases) iPad calculator apps, I wrote one myself.
The app store won&amp;rsquo;t make you any money. So why do people keep trying to monetize even the most basic apps? I decided to write simple free open-source apps for everyone, starting with a calculator.
After an unsatisfactory selection of free (free to download, no ads/tracking or in app purchases) iPad calculator apps, I wrote and open sourced my own using React Native.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>