<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stock market on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/stock-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stock market on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/stock-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 3 - Incentives</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-28-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-28-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-3/</guid>
      <description>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 3 — Incentives Renaissance Technologies is the most successful hedge fund in history, netting investors an average of 39% a year after fees over the last 3 decades. Renaissance stands out among its peers as by far the best performing fund.
 One reason is that the incentives Renaissance decided to focus on are different than that of other funds.
This is part 3 of my thoughts on Renaissance Technologies after reading The Man Who Solved the Market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 2 - Hiring Academics</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-20-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-20-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Renaissance Technologies is the most successful hedge fund in history, averaging nearly 40% annual net returns over the last 30 years. The book The Man Who Solved the Market discusses the fund and its founder Jim Simons in depth.
This is part 2 on a series discussing the book. Part 1 discussed the Renaissance’s data pipeline. This part will discuss Renaissance’s unusual practice of hiring almost exclusively from academia.
Academia Simons was a successful mathematician prior to starting Renaissance at the age of 40.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 1 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-19-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-19-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The new book The Man Who Solved the Market details Jim Simons and his hedge fund Renaissance Technologies in great detail. Jim Simons is a world renowned mathematician that left academia and started a hedge fund at the age of 40. He went on to become the most successful hedge fund manager and one of the richest people in the world.
The crown jewel of Renaissance Technologies is the Medallion Fund.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>