<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raspberry Pi on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raspberry Pi on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Offline Object Detection and Tracking on a Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-05-09_offline-object-detection-and-tracking-on-a-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-05-09_offline-object-detection-and-tracking-on-a-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>Load and run YOLO (You Only Look Once) object detection model on a Raspberry Pi and track objects throughout the day.
In my last post I wrote about the YOLO model used for object detection. The most surprising thing was how simple the model is. It’s so simple that it can run offline on a raspberry pi
In my last post I wrote about the YOLO (You Only Look Once) model used for object detection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to (actually) easily detect objects with deep learning on raspberry pi</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-04-05_how-to-actually-easily-detect-objects-with-deep-learning-on-raspberry-pi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-04-05_how-to-actually-easily-detect-objects-with-deep-learning-on-raspberry-pi/</guid>
      <description>YOLO provides state of the art real-time object detection and classification.
The YOLO image detection model is one of the fastest and most accurate object detection models. Flexible and fast, YOLO is a huge step forward in machine learning.
I came across a popular post on hackernews titled How to easily Detect Objects with Deep Learning on Raspberry Pi. The article discusses the YOLO object detection model that can be used for real-time object detection and classification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>