<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Facial Recognition on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/facial-recognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Facial Recognition on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/facial-recognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How Facial Recognition Works Part 3, How a Face Changes Over 10 Years</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-09-23-how-facial-recognition-works-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-09-23-how-facial-recognition-works-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is part 3 of a series of posts about facial recognition. In part 1 I discussed facial detection and part 2 I discussed facial landmarks. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go into how accurate some off the shelf facial recognition are and how well they work as a subject ages.
I found this video of a man (boy?) that took a picture of himself every day over 10 years starting at age 12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Facial Recognition Works Part 2, Facial Landmarks</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-07-16-how-facial-recognition-works-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-07-16-how-facial-recognition-works-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I discussed how face detection works. In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how landmark detection works.
Python offers some great free libraries for face recognition. Sorry, thats a lie. They offer great wrappers for C++ libraries like dlib. Using face_recognition, we can identify the face locations of an image is as simple as face_recognition.face_locations.
When talking about what distinguishes one face from another we normally talk about facial landmarks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Facial Recognition Works Part 1: Face Detection</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-07-08-how-facial-recognition-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-07-08-how-facial-recognition-works/</guid>
      <description>Much has been written about facial recognition and its role in society. As with a lot of topics concerning artificial intelligence, it is often discussed with an air of mysticism, as though all the all seeing machines can now peer into our souls. Depending on the narrative of the piece, its accuracy is chillingly accurate or appallingly inadequate for use. Amazon got flack for pitching their Reckognition service to law enforcement, San Fransisco banned the technology, and it has even been called racist.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>