<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nassim-taleb on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/nassim-taleb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nassim-taleb on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/nassim-taleb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassim Taleb, Loaded Questions and Statistics for Hackers</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-03-12_nassim-taleb-loaded-questions-and-statistics-for-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-03-12_nassim-taleb-loaded-questions-and-statistics-for-hackers/</guid>
      <description>Nassim Taleb baits financial professionals and students into an elementary mistake in probability. However a simple check could have helped.
Probability and statistics is hard and not always intuitive. But with modern computing, we can run simulations to get the answers, or at least tell us when we’re way off. Here I describe such methods.
In anticipation of reading Nassim Taleb’s new book Skin in the Game, I came across a paper Taleb wrote titled “We Don’t Quite Know What We Are Talking About When We Talk About Volatility”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nassim Taleb, Absorbing Barriers and House Money</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-03-07_nassim-taleb-absorbing-barriers-and-house-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-03-07_nassim-taleb-absorbing-barriers-and-house-money/</guid>
      <description>A recent EconTalk podcast featured Nassim Taleb in which he spoke about his new book Skin in the Game. During the discussion, he criticized…
A recent EconTalk podcast featured Nassim Taleb in which he spoke about his new book Skin in the Game. During the discussion, he criticized behavioral economists and social scientists for designing “one-shot” type experiments and trying to draw real life insights from the results. When in actuality, the more reasonable scenario is a series of interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>