<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finance on ML-Everything</title>
    <link>https://breeko.github.io/tags/finance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finance on ML-Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://breeko.github.io/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Bet Size Using Kelly Criterion</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2020-03-09-optimal-bet-size-using-kelly-criterion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2020-03-09-optimal-bet-size-using-kelly-criterion/</guid>
      <description>Optimal Bet Size Using Kelly Criterion TLDR: When placing a wager, choosing a bet size is as important as an edge. Kelly Criterion is a simple formula that determines the bet size for the highest growth in repeated games. I made a calculator/simulator to play out alternative strategies.
Suppose I offered you to play a game where we flip coins using a fair coin. If it lands on tails, you lose $1, but if it lands on heads, you win $1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Home in the US is Increasingly Attainable</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2020-02-28-buying-a-home-is-increasingly-affordable/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2020-02-28-buying-a-home-is-increasingly-affordable/</guid>
      <description>Buying a Home in the US is Increasingly Attainable There’s a common belief that the American dream is dead. One of the causes is home affordability. But buying a home is actually incredibly affordable now relative to the last 50 years when you consider mortgage rates and median income.
All charts below have been made by Chart It, a free tool I created for creating and sharing charts.
History of 30 Year Fixed Rate Mortgages Today the most popular mortgage loan in the US is the 30 year mortgage, but this wasn’t always the case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 3 - Incentives</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-28-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-28-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-3/</guid>
      <description>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 3 — Incentives Renaissance Technologies is the most successful hedge fund in history, netting investors an average of 39% a year after fees over the last 3 decades. Renaissance stands out among its peers as by far the best performing fund.
 One reason is that the incentives Renaissance decided to focus on are different than that of other funds.
This is part 3 of my thoughts on Renaissance Technologies after reading The Man Who Solved the Market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 2 - Hiring Academics</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-20-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-20-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Renaissance Technologies is the most successful hedge fund in history, averaging nearly 40% annual net returns over the last 30 years. The book The Man Who Solved the Market discusses the fund and its founder Jim Simons in depth.
This is part 2 on a series discussing the book. Part 1 discussed the Renaissance’s data pipeline. This part will discuss Renaissance’s unusual practice of hiring almost exclusively from academia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Renaissance Technologies Solved the Market: Part 1 - Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-19-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2019-11-19-how-renaissance-technologies-solved-the-market-part-1/</guid>
      <description>The new book The Man Who Solved the Market details Jim Simons and his hedge fund Renaissance Technologies in great detail. Jim Simons is a world renowned mathematician that left academia and started a hedge fund at the age of 40. He went on to become the most successful hedge fund manager and one of the richest people in the world.
The crown jewel of Renaissance Technologies is the Medallion Fund.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting the Stock Market, p-Hacking and Why You Should Be Bullish</title>
      <link>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-11-29-predicting-the-stock-market-p-hacking-and-why-you-should-be-bullish/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breeko.github.io/post/2018-11-29-predicting-the-stock-market-p-hacking-and-why-you-should-be-bullish/</guid>
      <description>Stock prices are just a series of numbers. Let’s try to fit a model to those numbers. What could go wrong?
With the rise of stock market volatility in the last few months, there has been a renewed interest in the stock market. The stock market is a compelling challenge to engineers. It’s a mature market with practically unlimited depth and exceptionally low transaction costs. If you can digest the numbers and eek out a model that is just slightly better than random, you would have investors lining up to give you their money.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>